Finding Aid for Michigan Environmental Council records, 1925-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Policy Advisor's Files (David Dempsey)
  - Public Employees for Environmental Responsibility (PEER) Report on DEQ (with Related Material), 1997-1998 (Box 29)
  - Sand Dune Protection
    - Background Information on Lake Michigan Dunes, 1925-1989 (Box 29)
    - Correspondence with Don Wilson, 2000 (Box 29)
    - General Information and Related Materials, 1994-2001 (Box 29)
    - Hope for the Dunes Organizational Records (from Don Wilson), 1976-1989 (Box 29)
    - MEC Activity, 1995-2001 (Box 29)
  - Sewer Infrastructure, 2000 (Box 29)
  - Sportfish Consumption Advisory, 2004 (Box 29)
  - Tip of the Mitt Watershed Council Grant Proposal for Citizen Involvement, 2000 (Box 29)
  - Underground Storage Tank Program, 1998-1999 (Box 29)
  - Walkinshaw Wetlands, 1992-1993 (Box 29)
  - "Water Quality and Pollution Control in Michigan" (DEQ Report), 2000 (Box 29)
  - Wetland Easements, 2003 (Box 29)
  - W.R. Grace and Co. (Ammonia Contamination), 2000; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - "Wyandotte: A Chemically Dependent City" (Report), 1989 (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous DEQ and MI Government Issues, 1996-1998 (Box 29)
- Land Programs Director's Files
  The Land Programs Director's Files series is comprised of three sub-series (in addition to the general sub-series, Other) based upon the individuals who have held this position since its inception in 1994 until 2008: Julie Stoneman, Conan Smith, and Brad Garmon. The Land Programs Director is intimately involved in MEC's Land Stewardship Initiative and oversees the various aspects of the council's land use programs.
  - Julie Stoneman
    Julie Stoneman's files include her business correspondence from 1994 until her departure in 1998 as well as records related to her work on Michigan Drain Code Revision and Takings legislation. MEC's Land Stewardship Initiative (LSI) is particularly well documented in this sub-series, which includes biweekly updates of LSI activities from the Michigan Environmental Reporter newsletter. The series includes information on mini-grants awarded by MEC to other environmental groups as part of LSI as well as separate grants provided in conjunction with the Michigan Economic and Environmental Roundtable (MEER). Stoneman's records also document MEC's interaction with Michigan Integrated Food and Farming Systems and the One Michigan Initiative.
    - Burt Lake, 1998 (Box 29)
    - Case Study: How a Small Foundation Addresses Land Use, 1999 (Box 29)
    - Coastal Zone Management, 1996 (Box 29)
    - Correspondence
      - 1994-1995 (Box 29)
      - 1996 (Box 29)
      - 1997-1998 (Box 29)
      - 1999 (Box 30)
    - Drain Code Revision, 1997-1999 (Box 30)
    - Fiscal Impacts of Sprawl (Various Reports), 1995-1998 (Box 30)
    - Great Lakes Protection Fund, 1998 (Box 30)
    - Great Lakes Pollution Prevention Alliance Member Directory, 1994 (Box 30)
    - Growing Smarter Regional Workshops, 1999 (Box 30)
    - Land Information Access Association, 1998-1999 (Box 30)
    - Land Stewardship Initiative (LSI)
      - General Information, 1996 (Box 30)
      - Leadership Workshop on Land Use, 1996 (Box 30)
      - Michigan Directory of Partnerships for Sustainable Development, 1996-1999 (Box 30)
      - Michigan Environmental Reporter: Biweekly Updates
        - 1994-1995 (Box 30)
        - 1996 (Box 30)
        - 1997 (Box 30)
        - 1998-1999 (Box 30)
      - Mini-Grants (Awarded by MEC)
        - Citizens Against Chemical Contamination, 1995-1996 (Box 30)
        - Clean Water Action, 1995-1997 (Box 30)
        - Detroit Audubon Society, 1995 (Box 30)
        - Ecology Center of Ann Arbor, 1995-1997 (Box 30)
        - East Michigan Environmental Action Council (EMEAC), 1995-1996 (Box 30)
        - Friends of the Jordan River, 1996-1997 (Box 30)
        - Huron River Watershed Council, 1995-1997 (Box 30)
        - Lake Michigan Federation, 1996-1999 (Box 30)
        - League of Women Voters (LWV) of the Copper Country, 1996-1997 (Box 30)
        - League of Women Voters (LWV) of Detroit, 1997 (Box 30)
        - League of Women Voters (LWV) of Michigan, 1995-1999 (Box 30)
        - Michigan Audubon Society, 1996 (Box 30)
        - Michigan Land Use Institute (MLUI), 1996-1999 (Box 30)
        - Michigan Natural Areas Council, 1995-1999 (Box 30)
        - Mid Michigan Environmental Action Council (Mid-MEAC), 1996-1998 (Box 30)
        - Oakland Land Conservancy, 1996-1997 (Box 30)
        - Pottawatomie Land Trust, 1995-1998 (Box 30)
        - Public Interest Research Group in Michigan (PIRGIM), 1999 (Box 30)
        - Rails to Trails Conservancy, 1997-1998 (Box 30)
        - Southeast Michigan Land Conservancy, 1995 (Box 30)
        - Tip of the Mitt Watershed Council, 1996-1999 (Box 30)
        - United Growth for Kent County, 1999 (Box 31)
        - Upper Peninsula Environmental Council (UPEC), 1995-1996 (Box 31)
        - West Michigan Environmental Action Council (WMEAC), 1995-1998 (Box 31)
        - General Grant Information, 1999 (Box 31)
      - Strategic Plans, 1995-1996 (Box 31)
    - Land Use Initiative Planning Reports, 1994 (Box 31)
    - Land Use Training Workshop, 1995 (Box 31)
    - League of Women Voters of Michigan Frey Foundation Grant, 1998 (Box 31)
    - Livable Communities Conference, 1996 (Box 31)
    - MEC Member Questionnaire on Land Work, 1994 (Box 31)
    - Michigan Economic and Environmental Roundtable (MEER)
      - Mini-Grants
        - Bay County Environmental Affairs and Community Development, 1997-1998 (Box 31)
        - Calhoun County Community Development/Battle Creek Association of Home Builders, 1999 (Box 31)
        - Chestonia Township and the Partners for Environmentally Educated Communities (PEEC), 1997-1998 (Box 31)
        - Forum for Kalamazoo County, 1998-1999 (Box 31)
        - Four-Township Water Resources Council, Inc., 1997-1998 (Box 31)
        - Grand Traverse Regional Land Conservancy, 1997 (Box 31)
        - Lakeshore Center for Independent Living, 1997-1998 (Box 31)
        - Macomb County Farmland and Open Space Preservation, 1997-1998 (Box 31)
        - Michigan State University Extension/Kirtland Community College Partnership, 1997-1998 (Box 31)
        - Michigan Outdoors Habitat Brokerage, Inc. (MOHBI), 1999 (Box 31)
        - General Grant Information, 1997-1999 (Box 31)
      - Meeting Agenda, Reports, etc., 1997-1999 (Box 31)
    - Michigan Integrated Food and Farming Systems (MIFFS)
      - Activities, 1995-1998 (Box 31)
      - MEC Reports to MIFFS, 1994-1997 (Box 31)
      - Organizational Records, Correspondence, etc., 1997-1999 (Box 31)
    - National Growth Management Leadership Conference (Hosted by MEC), 1996 (Box 31)
    - One Michigan Initiative, 1996-1998; 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Partners in Statewide Conservation Planning, 1998-1999 (Box 31)
    - Sierra Club
      - Forest Management Issues, 1994-1995 (Box 31)
      - Mackinac Chapter Faith Based Initiative, 1997-1999 (Box 31)
    - Takings Legislation
      - Anti-Takings Bills, 1995 (Box 31)
      - Clippings, 1994-1996 (Box 31)
      - Correspondence, 1994-1999 (Box 31)
      - HB 4433, 1995-1996 (Box 31)
      - Homeowners Protection Act, 1995 (Box 31)
      - MEC Position, undated, 1989 (Box 31)
      - Michigan Takings, 1989-1996 (Box 31)
      - Nordhouse Dunes Takings Appeal, 1994 (Box 31)
      - Publications, 1994-1999 (Box 31)
      - Reports, 1993-1997 (Box 31)
      - Roundtable Discussion, 1995 (Box 32)
      - Satellite Conference on Takings and Land Use, 1998 (Box 32)
      - General Reference Materials, 1994-1997 (Box 32)
    - Trends, 1996-1998 (Box 32)
    - Ultimate Farmland Preservation Tour, 1999 (Box 32)
    - Urban Sprawl Stakeholders Group, 1999 (Box 32)
    - "Urban Vision: An Agenda for the Future of Michigan Cities" (Presentation to MI House of Representatives), 1998 (Box 32)
    - US Route 23 Extension, 1994-1995 (Box 32)
    - Washtenaw County Land Use, 1995-1998; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Workshops (Various), 1996-1999 (Box 32)
  - Conan Smith
    The Conan Smith sub-series contains similar content related to LSI and MEER in addition to a wide-range of materials related to transportation issues and Smart Growth (an MEC initiative which focused on environmentally-friendly urban planning and development).
    - Active Projects, 2001 (Box 32)
    - American Thought and Language (ATL) 135 Course Materials, 2002 (Box 32)
    - Build Michigan III, 2000-2002 (Box 32)
    - Citizens Against Bigger Trucks (CABT), 1998-2002 (Box 32)
    - Citizens Committed to Preserving Cherry Run, 2003 (Box 32)
    - Communication Strategies and Ideas, 1999-2004 (Box 32)
    - Creating Cool: Linking Culture, Community and Economy (Forum and Related Materials), 2003 (Box 32)
    - Detroit Area Regional Transit Authority (RTA), 2001-2002 (Box 32)
    - Electronic Media, 1999 (Box 32)
    - Environmental Briefing Book, 1999 (Box 32)
    - Environmental Communications and Community Organizing (ECCO) Initiative, 2000-2003 (Box 32)
    - Environmental Law and Policy Center, 1999 (Box 32)
    - Events, 2000-2001 (Box 32)
    - Faith-Based MEC Partners, 1997-2001 (Box 32)
    - Fancher (Dusty): Michigan Environmental Reporter Articles, 2000 (Box 32)
    - The "Filthy Five" of Michigan (Corporate Pollution), 1997 (Box 32)
    - "Fix it First" Campaign (Road Repair and Public Act 51), 1999-2000 (Box 32)
    - General Motors and Delta Township Air Quality, 2002 (Box 32)
    - Grants (Awarded to MEC)
      - Americana Foundation, 2000 (Box 32)
      - Environmental Protection Agency, 2001-2002 (Box 32)
      - Ford Motor Company Fund, 2000 (Box 32)
      - Frey Foundation, 2000 (Box 32)
      - Mott Foundation, 2000-2004 (Box 32)
      - People and Land (PAL), 2002-2004 (Box 32)
      - General Deliverables, 2001 (Box 32)
    - Growth Management Leadership Alliance, 1996-2003; 3 folders (Box 33)
    - House Bipartisan Urban Caucus, 2000 (Box 33)
    - House Land Use Task Force and Work Group, 1999-2001 (Box 33)
    - House Local Government and Urban Affairs Committee, 1999 (Box 33)
    - Land Stewardship Initiative (LSI)
      - Mini-Grants
        - East Michigan Environmental Action Council (EMEAC), 1999-2001 (Box 33)
        - Great Lakes Bioregional Land Conservancy, 1999-2000 (Box 33)
        - Michigan Land Use Institute (MLUI), 2000-2001 (Box 33)
        - Oakland Land Conservancy, 1999-2000 (Box 33)
        - Rails to Trails Conservancy, 1999-2000 (Box 33)
        - Tip of the Mitt Watershed Council, 1999-2000 (Box 33)
        - Washtenaw-Pottawatomie Land Trust, 2000 (Box 33)
        - General Grant Information, 2000 (Box 33)
      - Meeting Agendas, Reports, etc., 2000-2002 (Box 33)
      - Strategic Plans, 2000-2003 (Box 33)
    - League of Conservation Voters (LCV) Summer Academy, 1999 (Box 33)
    - Legislation
      - Farmland Protection, 2000-2003 (Box 33)
      - HB 4632 (Roadside Brush Cuts), 1999 (Box 33)
      - HB 4803 (Drain Code Revision) and Related Bills, 1998-2000 (Box 33)
      - Proposal 2 (MI Natural Resources Trust Fund Investment), 2002 (Box 33)
      - SB 205 (Land Use for Agriculture), 1999 (Box 33)
      - SB 364 (Department of Environmental Quality Urban Redevelopment), 1999 (Box 33)
      - Hearings, Correspondence, and General Information, 2000-2003 (Box 33)
    - Livingston County Community Forum, 2000 (Box 33)
    - "Making a Difference" MEC Initiative, 2001-2002 (Box 33)
    - Meetings (Various), 2001 (Box 33)
    - Michigan Economic Development Corporation, 1999 (Box 33)
    - Michigan Economic and Environmental Roundtable (MEER)
      - Mini-Grants
        - Alpine Township, 1999-2000 (Box 33)
        - American Farmland Trust, 2001 (Box 33)
        - Arab Community Center for Economic and Social Services (ACCESS), 1999-2002 (Box 33)
        - Bay County Department of Environmental Affairs and Community Development, 1999-2000 (Box 33)
        - Community Foundation of Monroe County, 2002-2004 (Box 33)
        - Detroit River Remedial Action Plan Team, 2002 (Box 33)
        - Eastside Industrial Council, 1999-2000 (Box 33)
        - Friends of Martz Park, 2002 (Box 33)
        - Great Lakes Bioregional Land Conservancy, 2001-2002 (Box 33)
        - Jefferson East Business Association, 1999-2000 (Box 33)
        - Kalamazoo College, 1999-2000 (Box 33)
        - Keewenaw Land Trust, Inc., 1999-2000 (Box 33)
        - Kent/Michigan State University Extension, 2001-2002 (Box 33)
        - Lapeer Conservation District, 2002 (Box 33)
        - Metropolitan Organizing Strategy Enabling Strength (MOSES), 2001 (Box 33)
        - Michigan Farmland and Community Alliance, 2000-2002 (Box 33)
        - Michigan Integrated Food and Farming Systems (MIFFS), 2001 (Box 33)
        - Michigan Land Use Institute (MLUI), 2001-2002 (Box 34)
          (includes CD-ROM with Word and Excel documents relating to the grant)
        - Michigan Organic Food and Farm Alliance, 2002 (Box 34)
        - Michigan United Conservation Clubs (MUCC), 2001 (Box 34)
        - Midland Conservation District, 2001-2002 (Box 34)
        - Mid-Michigan Environmental Action Council (Mid-MEAC), 2001-2002 (Box 34)
        - Montmorency County Coordinated Township Planning Committee, 1999-2000 (Box 34)
        - Saginaw Basin Land Conservancy, 2002 (Box 34)
        - Scenic Michigan, 2002 (Box 34)
        - SEEDS, 2002 (Box 34)
        - Southwest Michigan Leadership Foundation Inc., 2002 (Box 34)
        - Timber, 2002 (Box 34)
        - Top of Michigan Trails Council, 2001 (Box 34)
      - General Grant Information, 2000 (Box 34)
      - General Grant Information, 2001 (Box 34)
      - General Grant Information, 2002 (Box 34)
      - Land Use Leadership Training Program, 2000 (Box 34)
      - Meetings, Correspondence, and General Information, 1996-2001 (Box 34)
    - Michigan Environmental Law Center (MELC) Strategic Plan, 1999 (Box 34)
    - Michigan Land Use Funders, 2003 (Box 34)
    - "Michigan's Sand Dune Reserve Program" (DNR Publication), 1996 (Box 34)
    - Michigan Society of Planning Annual Conference packet, 2000 (Box 34)
    - Michigan State University Land Policy Program Retreat, 2003 (Box 34)
    - Michigan Transportation and Land Use Coalition, 1999-2003; 3 folders (Box 34)
    - Milan Township Land Use, 2000 (Box 34)
    - New Directions Initiative, 2001 (Box 34)
    - Open Space Community Planning, 1995-2000s (Box 34)
    - Partnership for Redevelopment in Michigan, 2000-2004 (Box 34)
    - Press Releases, 2001-2002 (Box 34)
    - Scenic Michigan, 2000-2001 (Box 34)
    - Smart Growth
      - Campaign Strategies and Proposals, 1999-2003 (Box 34)
      - Goals, 2000-2002 (Box 34)
      - Manufactured Housing Issues, 1993-2000 (Box 34)
      - Trademark Dispute (on "Smart Growth" term), 2000 (Box 34)
      - Workshops
        - Bengel Wildlife Center (Bath, MI), 2000 (Box 34)
        - Detroit, 2001 (Box 34)
        - Grand Rapids, undated (Box 34)
        - Traverse City, 2001 (Box 34)
    - Smith (Conan) Business Records
      - Correspondence, 2001-2004 (Box 34)
      - Photographs, 1990s-2000s (Box 34)
      - Royal Oak Area Democratic Club (ROADC) Speech, 1999 (Box 34)
      - Writings (and Supporting Materials), 1999-2002; 1 floppy disks 3.5" (Box 34)
        (includes 3.5" floppy disc with MS Word Documents)
      - Work Plan, 2002 (Box 34)
    - Southern Michigan Trails Program, 1999-2002 (Box 35)
    - Sprawl Action Resource Centers (SpARCs), 2004 (Box 35)
    - Staff Management Plan, 2000s (Box 35)
    - Transportation Issues
      - Alternative Fuels, 1999-2000 (Box 35)
      - "Comparing Maintenance to Capital Outlay" (MEC Report and Research Materials), circa 2000 (Box 35)
      - Context Sensitive Design (Transportation Planning), 2002-2003 (Box 35)
      - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 35)
      - "Defining Transportation Investment Priorities" (MEC and MLUI Presentation), 1990s (Box 35)
      - "Fiscal Responsibility in Transportation Spending in the Upper Mid-West" (MEC Report), circa 2000 (Box 35)
      - Fuel Prices, 2000 (Box 35)
      - High Speed Rail, 1998-2002 (Box 35)
      - HB 4002 (Transit Fund Increase), 2001-2002 (Box 35)
      - Interstate 31 and Bypass, 1996-1998 (Box 35)
      - Interstate 73 Feasibility Study, 1999-2000 (Box 35)
      - Lansing to Detroit Passenger Rail Service, 1997-2001 (Box 35)
      - Lobbying, 1998-2003 (Box 35)
      - Michigan Transportation Summit, 2003 (Box 35)
      - Public Act 51 (Transportation Spending), 1999-2000 (Box 35)
      - SB 1274 and 1275 (Transportation Funding), 2000 (Box 35)
      - State Long Range Transportation Plan and Related Materials, 2000 (Box 35)
      - Statistics, 1998-1999 (Box 35)
      - Traffic Reduction, 1998 (Box 35)
      - "Transportation Teach-In" (Sponsored by DWEJ), 1999 (Box 35)
      - Trends, 1995-1996 (Box 35)
    - Transportation Riders United Annual Plan, 2001 (Box 35)
    - Tri-County Regional Planning Commission, 2000-2003 (Box 35)
    - The Ultimate Land Use Conference, 2000 (Box 35)
    - Urban Sprawl (Miscellaneous Reports), 1995-2002 (Box 35)
    - Web Site Development (MEC), 1999 (Box 35)
    - West Michigan Strategic Alliance, 2000-2004 (Box 35)
  - Brad Garmon
    The Brad Garmon sub-series has similar material in addition to files that deal with issues such as mining, urban sprawl, and context-sensitive design.
    - Active Michigan Initiative (AMI), 2003-2004 (Box 35)
    - Context Sensitive Design (Transportation Planning), 2002-2006 (Box 35)
    - Designing Healthy and Livable Communities (DHLC) Conference Planning, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Gilliam, Kim (MEC Fundraising Consultant), 2004 (Box 35)
    - Healthy Communities, 2004-2008 (Box 35)
    - Healthy Kids, Healthy Michigan, 2007-2008 (Box 35)
    - MEC Land Program Goals, Activities, and Partnerships, 2004 (Box 35)
    - Michigan Land Use Partners, 2003 (Box 35)
    - Michigan Non-Motorized Transportation and Outdoor Recreation Coalition (MNRTC) and Related Initiatives, 2000-2006 (Box 35)
    - Mining Issues: Legislation, Correspondence, Reports, and Related Meetings, 1994-2005; 3 folders (Box 36)
    - Partnership for Redevelopment in Michigan, 2005 (Box 36)
    - "The Role of Corporate Timberland Ownership Change in Land Use, Conservation, and Local Prosperity in Michigan's Upper Peninsula" (PAL/NWF Grant Project and Related Materials), 2006-2007 (Box 36)
    - Schools and Sprawl (Various Reports), 2000-2003 (Box 36)
    - "Smart Growth For Clean Water" (DEQ Coastal Management Grant Project includes Reports, Conference Materials, Correspondence, etc.), 2003-2006; 2 folders (Box 36)
    - "Sprawling of America" (Materials related to Video Documentary), 2002-2003 (Box 36)
    - State Long Range Transportation Plan Workshop and Related Materials, 2006 (Box 36)
    - Timberland Zoning and Planning, 2006 (Box 36)
    - Transportation Enhancement Fund, 2002 (Box 36)
  - Other
    The Other sub-series contains undated material that could not be attributed to any one individual as well as the 2012 accession's Land Program files, which are combined from the tenures of Stoneman, Smith and Garmon.
    - Environmental Quality and Economic Development, undated (Box 36)
    - Land Use Resource Guide Summary, undated (Box 36)
    - Michigan Natural River Program, undated (Box 36)
    - National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA), 1990-1999 (Box 36)
    - Purchase of Development Rights, undated (Box 36)
    - Wastewater Lagoons, undated (Box 36)
    - 4 Towns Citizens Action Team, 2004 (Box 51)
    - Active Michigan Initiative, 2002-2003 (Box 51)
    - Advisory Groups, 2002-2003 (Box 51)
    - Agricultural Security Areas, 1995 (Box 51)
    - Agriculture, 1994-1999; 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Biodiversity Project, 1996-1999 (Box 51)
    - Biodiversity Project-Chicago Meeting, Great Lakes Compact, 2008 (Box 51)
    - Census Bureau, 1997-1998 (Box 51)
    - "Citizen-Based Organizations in Growth Management" (Report), 2000 (Box 51)
    - Citizens Alliance for Regulatory Reform (CARR), 1995 (Box 51)
    - Citizens Research Council of Michigan Budget Outlook, 2002 (Box 51)
    - "Community, Character and Cash: How You can Reform Transportation with Context Sensitive Solutions" (Report), 2005 (Box 51)
    - Concentrated Animal Feeding Operations (CAFOs), 1997-1999 (Box 51)
    - Cranbrook-Kingswood Project Quarry, 2000 (Box 51)
    - Cross-Cutting Issues Technical Work Group, 2007-2008 (Box 51)
    - Crystal River, 1997-1999 (Box 51)
    - Directory of Partnerships for Sustainable Development, 1999 (Box 51)
    - Energy, 2006-2007 (Box 51)
    - Erb Family Foundation Annual Report, 2010 (Box 51)
    - Faith Resolution with Metropolitan Organizing Strategy Enabling Strength (MOSES), 1999 (Box 51)
    - Farmland and Open Space Preservation Act (Public Act 116), 1977-1995
    - Farmland Trust Fund, 1998 (Box 51)
    - Fiscal Impact, 1979-1994 (Box 51)
    - Fiscal Taxes, 1997-1998 (Box 51)
    - Food and Farming, 2006-2007 (Box 51)
    - Grand Traverse Growth Management, 1999-2000 (Box 51)
    - Grand Traverse Regional Land Conservancy (GTRLC) Project Greenfields, 1997-1998 (Box 51)
    - Grants
      - Cheboygan County Michigan State University Extension, 1997-1999 (Box 51)
      - Groundwater Education in Michigan Center (GEM)
        - Michigan Technological University, 1997 (Box 51)
        - Western Michigan University, 1997 (Box 51)
      - Michigan Economic and Environmental Roundtable (MEER) Small Grants Request, 1998 (Box 51)
      - Mini-Grants Program, 1995-1998 (Box 51)
      - Nature Conservancy/Les Cheneaux, 1997-1998 (Box 51)
      - Southwest Detroit Environmental Vision Project (SDEVP), 1997-1998 (Box 51)
    - Green Detroit Initiative, 2007-2008 (Box 51)
    - Growth Management, 1990-1999 (Box 52)
    - High Speed Rail, 1998-2000 (Box 52)
    - Land Division Act, 1997-1999 (Box 52)
    - Land Stewardship Initiative
      - Conference, 1995-1996 (Box 52)
      - Focus Groups, 1995-1996; 2 folders (Box 52)
      - General, 1994-1997 (Box 52)
      - Grassroots Organizations, 1999 (Box 52)
      - Marketing Strategy, 1996 (Box 52)
    - Land Use-General
      - 1991-1998 (Box 52)
      - 1999-2001 (Box 52)
      - 2004-2007 (Box 52)
    - Land Use Policy
      - Agenda, 1998-1999 (Box 52)
      - Federal, 1999 (Box 52)
      - State, 1996-1999 (Box 52)
    - Lansing-to-Detroit Passenger Rail, 2002 (Box 52)
    - Legislation
      - HB 4020 (Traffic Impact Fee Enabling Act), 1999-2001 (Box 52)
      - HB 4148 (Mobile Home Commission Act), 1999-2000 (Box 52)
      - HB 4156 (Plant Rehabilitation and Industrial Development Districts), 2001 (Box 52)
      - HB 4160 (Housing Freedom Zone), 2001 (Box 52)
      - HB 4174 (Revised Judicature Act), 2001 (Box 52)
      - HB 4181 (Mobile Home Commission Act), 2000 (Box 52)
      - HB 4199 (Mobile Home Commission Act), 2001 (Box 52)
      - HB 4244 (Homestead Relief Cap), 2001 (Box 52)
      - HB 4289-4291 (Township Zoning Act, City and Village Zoning Act, County Zoning Act), 2001 (Box 52)
      - HB 4400 SB 269, HB 5445 (General Property Tax Act, Single Business Tax Act, Brownfield Redevelopment Financing Act), 2000 (Box 52)
      - HB 4439 (County Zoning Act), 2001 (Box 52)
      - HB 4623 (Impact Fees), 1995-1996 (Box 52)
      - HB 4944 (Mobile Home Commission Act), 1999-2000 (Box 52)
      - HB 5516 (Trailer Parks Coach Act), 2000 (Box 52)
      - HB 5517 (General Sales Tax Act), 2000 (Box 52)
      - HB 5518 (Mobile Home Commission Act), 2000 (Box 52)
      - HB 5727-5729 (City and Village Zoning Act, County Zoning Act), 2000 (Box 52)
      - HB 5822 (Manufactured Homes), 2000 (Box 52)
      - HB 6487 (State Transportation Commission), 2002 (Box 52)
      - SB 43 (Mobile Home Commission Act), 1999-2000 (Box 52)
      - SB 159 (Natural Resources Protection Act), 2001 (Box 52)
      - SB 205 (Right to Farm), 1999 (Box 52)